UNITE Research Department Files 6000/020
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Research Department Files
1995-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE)
6000/020
4.5 cubic feet
4.5 linear ft.
Records.
This collection includes records of the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers of America (ACTWU) and the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
6791832
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 23, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000/020 P: UNITE Research Department Photographs 6000/014: UNITE Research Department Chronological Correspondence Files 6000/003: UNITE Research Department Historic Files 6000 AV: UNITE Audio-Visual Collection 6000 G: UNITE Posters 6000 MB: UNITE Memorabilia 6000 P: UNITE Photographs
Textile workers--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions; Collective bargaining--Clothing industry; Collective bargaining--Textile industry; Plant shutdowns; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Research Department--Archives; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives
6791832
- NAFTA AFL-CIO Reports (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NAFTA Economic Policy Institute Studies (Box 1, Folder 2)
- NAFTA International Trade Commission Studies (Box 1, Folder 3)
- NAFTA/Mercosur - Other FTA (Box 1, Folder 4)
- NAFTA National Admin Office (NAO) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- NAFTA Plants Moved to Mexico (Box 1, Folder 6)
- NAFTA Trade Adjustment Assistance (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Women and NAFTA (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CJM (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Failed Experiment NAFTA at three years (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Johnson & Johnson Proxy Statements, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- NAFTA - CBI Parity (Box 1, Folder 13)
- NAFTA Expansion off the Fast Track on the Right Track (Box 1, Folder 14)
- NAFTA Hits Apparel Jobs Hard: Study (Box 1, Folder 15)
- NAFTA Studies (Box 1, Folder 16)
- NAFTA's Broken Promises The Border Betrayed (Box 1, Folder 17)
- NAFTA's First Two Years The Myths and Realities (Box 1, Folder 18)
- NAFTA's Labor Side Agreement Lessons From the First Three Years (Box 1, Folder 19)
- North American Free Trade and Investment Report Volume S, Number 19, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- North American Free Trade and Investment Report, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Scope and Contents
  Volume 6
- North American Fair Trade and Investment Report Volume 7, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- North American Free Trade and Investment Report volume 8, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- North American Free Trade and Investment Report Volume 9, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- North American Labor Series (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Runaways, the (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Study on the Operations and Effects of the NAFTA (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Working Together: Labor report on the Americas, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  July-August
- World Trade (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Biography: Evy Dubrow (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Business for Social Responsibility (Box 1, Folder 31)
- CBI (Box 1, Folder 32)
- CBI Parity (Box 1, Folder 33)
- IUD (Box 1, Folder 34)
- The International Competitiveness of the Costa Rica Clothing Industry (Box 1, Folder 35)
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union Min Matheson (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Jewish Labor Committees (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Jobs with Justice (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Lowell National Historical Park (Box 1, Folder 39)
- The Myth of the Coming Labor Shortage (Box 1, Folder 40)
- NYS DMV (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Plate Check Registration (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Solomon Barkin (Box 1, Folder 43)
- IUD Technology Working Group (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Sweatshop Campaign (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Sweatshop Campaign (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sweatshop Campaign - Campus (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Sweatshop Campaign Graphic (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sweatshop Campaign - Code of Conduct (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sweatshop Cost Analysis (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sweatshops: Fashion Summit (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Stop Sweatshop News" (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Special Projects: Sweatshops Task Force, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Video Sweatshops (Box 2, Folder 9)
- International Trade correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  November 95 - June 96
- International Trade Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  July - November
- UNITE Photos and Clippings (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Lake Research (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Costume Makers Campaign (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Polling Lake Research (Box 3, Folder 3)
- NAFTA Articles (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Trade Correspondence: H. Starobin, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Statements filed by UNITE, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  February 28, onward
- Trade - NAFTA - Labor Accords (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NAFTA - NAALC (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NAFTA Memos/Announcements (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Trade - NAFTA Fast Track (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NAFTA Impact (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Reform Senate Hearing (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Courtaulds (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Cranston Print Works (Box 3, Folder 14)
- D C B Apparel (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Dominion Textiles (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Duro Industries (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Farah (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Fieldcrest (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Freudenbergs Nonwovens (Box 3, Folder 20)
- house of Ronnie, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Jefferson Mills (Box 3, Folder 22)
- J.H. Collectibles (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Jockey International (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Kitchens of the Ocean, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Jonbil (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Johnson & Johnson Financial and General (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Kalkstein Silk Mills (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Letchers (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Levi Strauss (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Levi Strauss & co. (Organizing) (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Macintosh Linen & Uniform Rental, Inc. Local 128C (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Allentown, PA
- Levi Strauss Financial and General (Box 3, Folder 33)
- London Fog (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Macy's R.H. & Co. (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Maiden Form (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Majestic Shapes (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Malden Mills (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Marks & Spencer (Brooks Brothers Inc.) (New York Organizing) (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Masland (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Mohawk Industries Inc. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- May Department Stores News Clippings (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New Balance Inc. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Oneita Industries Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Phillips - Van Heusen (Box 4, Folder 6)
- SPX Corp. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Sabratek Corp. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- SCT Yarns (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Safer Prints Inc. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sanyo Fashions (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Springs industries (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Talbots (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Textile Leather (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Tri-con Industries (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Guess Campaign (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Owens-Corning Hunt (Box 4, Folder 17)
- General Cable (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Gencorp (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Venture Stores (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Vittandini Adrienne (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Warren Corp. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Wellman Inc., General and Financial (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Wellman Inc. News Clippings (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Wellman Inc. Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 25)
- West Mill Clothes (Box 4, Folder 26)
- West point Stevens, Inc. (Analyst Reports) (Box 4, Folder 27)
- West Point Stevens Inc. (401-k) (Box 4, Folder 28)
- West Point / Black Stone (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Westpoint Stevens Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 30)
- westpoint Stevens Financial & General (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Westpoint Stevens News Clippings (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Wolverine World Wide (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Peerless Clothing Inc. (Financial & General) (Box 4, Folder 34)
- YKK (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Zeta Consumer Products Corp. (Financial & General) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Zeta Consumer Products Financial and General (Box 5, Folder 3)